foodincmovie.com 2015-12-25

# Privacy Policy | TakePart

**Please note:** this video is only intended to highlight important information contained in the Privacy Policy and is not in any way intended to be a substitute for the official, legally binding document, which is found below.

* * *

Effective Date: This Privacy Policy was last revised on December 13, 2013. You may print this document for your records.

### _Introduction and Overview_

Welcome! You have arrived at [www.takepart.com](http://www.takepart.com/) (the “ **TakePart Website** ”) and/or you are otherwise interacting with our social action plug-in that may be made available through third-party sites and apps (the “ **Take Action Platform** ”), which Take Action Platform and TakePart Website are owned and operated by TakePart, LLC (“ **TakePart** ” or “ **we** ,” “ **our** ” or “ **us** ”), or with our other Service (defined below) offerings.This “ **Privacy Policy** ” governs your use of any online service location ( _e.g._ , web site or mobile app) including, without limitation, the TakePart Website, that posts a link to this Privacy Policy (each a “ **Site** ”). It also applies to your use of interactive features, widgets, plug-ins (like the Take Action Platform), applications, content, downloads or other services: (i) that we own or control and make available through a Site; or (ii) that posts a link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, with the Sites, the TakePart Website and the Take Action Platform, the " **Service** "). It applies regardless of how you access or use the Service, whether via personal computers, mobile devices or otherwise. This Privacy Policy does not, however, apply to our data collection activities offline or otherwise outside of our Service (unless otherwise stated below) and does not govern the data practices of third parties that may interact with the Service.

**To the extent we provide you notice on any Service of different or additional privacy policies or practices ( _e.g._ , at the point of our collection), those additional terms shall govern such data collection and use.**

In addition, please review our **[Terms of Service](http://www.takepart.com/terms-of-use)** , which governs your use of the Service. _By using any Service_ , _you consent to our Privacy Policy and **[Terms of Service](http://www.takepart.com/terms-of-use)** and our collection, use and sharing of your information and data, and other activities, as described below._

**_You should read this entire Privacy Policy, but to help facilitate your review, here is a partial list of some of the key topics we want to bring to your initial attention that are further detailed below._** The full detailed provisions govern over their respective summaries and headings. Capitalized terms have the meanings given to them where defined in the Privacy Policy.

  * **Click here for a summary of each section of the Privacy Policy.** You may click on the topic for full details, which govern.
  * The Service is a distributed experience that may interact with third-party services. Our Privacy Policy and **[Terms of Service](http://www.takepart.com/terms-of-use)** apply to our Service only and third-party services are subject to third-party terms and policies.
  * By accessing and using the Service, you acknowledge and consent to our privacy practices detailed in this Privacy Policy and agree to the posted **[Terms of Service](http://www.takepart.com/terms-of-use)**. In order to prospectively revoke your consent, you must: terminate your account, stop using the Service and uninstall any downloads and applications.
  * Third parties, including linked sites ( _e.g._ , Facebook), non-profits we work with, advertisers and advertising service providers, collect information about you in connection with your use of the Service ( _e.g._ , Usage Information). Further, third parties use Tracking Technologies in connection with our Service, which may include the collection of information about your online activities over time and across third-party web sites or online services. Their privacy policies, not ours, govern their practices. Click here.
  * Currently, we do not monitor or take any action with respect to third party signals for the expression of choice regarding collection of information about an individual over time and across third-party web sites or online services (e.g., browser do not track signals), but you may have certain other options regarding tracking and/or targeting.
  * We and third parties that interact with our Service may use technologies to track your activities on and off of the Service to better understand how to serve you, and based on this information you may be served with targeted content, social action opportunities and advertising. You may exercise certain opt-out elections regarding this.
  * The Service is a social media experience and your activities on or related to the Service, including your social actions and media consumption, may be shared with others on and off of the Service ( _e.g._ , Gabe signed the stop plastic grocery bags petition, you should too). In addition, you will have the opportunity to create a Profile, which Profile information will be available to others. However, we may provide you with settings to exercise certain options regarding such sharing.
  * We give you the opportunity to exercise choice regarding our sharing of your Personal Information with non-Affiliate third parties for their direct marketing purposes, but our Affiliates ( _e.g_., Participant Media) automatically have access to your Personal Information to market to you. California residents may request information about our sharing of certain information with our Affiliates for direct marketing. **Click here for more information.**

* * *

### _Linkable Privacy Policy_

It is important that you read and understand the entire Privacy Policy before using the Service. To ease review, each section below includes, as a courtesy, a heading and brief introductory summary linked to the full explanation, which full provision governs over headings and summaries. Click on the headings and the “ _Read more_ ” links to be taken to the details. Capitalized terms that appear but are not otherwise defined in the introduction have the meanings given to them elsewhere in the Privacy Policy, and you can click on them to go to that definition.

**1.What Information Does the Service Collect?**

We collect and receive information about you as you interact with our Service, explained further in this section. **Read more**

  1. **Information You Provide To Us**

We collect certain Personal Information and Demographic Information that you provide to us when you interact with the Service. For example, we may collect this information through various forms and in various places on the Service, including newsletter registration forms, through “contact us” forms, by taking an action such as signing an online petition, or when you otherwise interact with the Service. **Read more**

  1. **Information We Collect and Store as You Access and Use the Service**

We may collect certain information from you automatically when you access and use the Service. For example, we and third parties may use Tracking Technologies to collect Usage Information (i.e., non-Personal Information) based on your Device Identifier for a variety of purposes, including tracking, targeting, and advertising, which may include activities across time and third party locations. We do not look for or respond to do not track signals, but you avoid such tracking by not using the Service. You may have certain other choices regarding tracking and/or targeting. **Read more**

  1. **Information Third Parties Provide About You**

We may obtain information about you from third parties. This helps us learn more about how to send you relevant content and ads. To the extent this information is combined by us with Personal Information we collect via the Service, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy. The privacy policies of those third parties, not this Privacy Policy, govern those parties’ data practices. **Read more**

  1. **Interaction with Third-Party Sites**

If you interact with third-party sites, those sites may send us information about you and you or we may send them information about you. For example, if register for an account to access the Service, you may use Facebook Connect as part of the registration process and Facebook will automatically provide us with certain information you provided to Facebook. **Read more**

  1. **Information You Provide About a Third Party**

You may provide us information about others, such as when you send a friend a message. If so, the information you provide (names, e-mail addresses, mobile number, etc.) may be used to facilitate the communication, but will not be used for other marketing purposes unless your friend consents. You may be identified to the friend in connection with such message. **Read more**

**2.How Do We Use the Information Collected?**

We use your Personal Information, Demographic Information and Usage Information for a variety of purposes detailed in this section. For example, we use the information collected about you to help deliver a more personalized and relevant experience to users on our Service and to better understand how to effectively advertise and provide you the opportunity to take actions for causes that you care about. However, you have the opportunity to exercise certain opt-out options. **Read more**

**3.How and When Do We Share Information With Third Parties?**

We may provide your information to third parties under various circumstances detailed in this section, some of which you have choices regarding. Learn more about how to exercise those choices in this section. Learn more about how to exercise those choices in this section. Without limitation, these uses may include:

  1. **When You Request Information From or Provide Information to Third Parties**

If you request information from third parties, request that we send information to third parties or interact with third-party sites, content, ads or tools (including Facebook and other third-party share functionality) we may share your information with such parties and/or they may collect your information directly. **Read more**

  1. **Third Parties Providing Services on Our Behalf**

Our vendors may collect your information on our behalf or we may share it with them so that they may provide services to us and you. Some may offer you choices regarding the collection and use of your information. **Read more**

  1. **To Deliver Social Content and Advertising**

We may share or transfer your content and information in connection with our social media features and/or social advertising, which may specifically identify you and your activities ( _e.g._ , Gary volunteered at his local food bank) to people associated with you (such as members of your social networks). However, you have the opportunity to exercise certain opt-out options. **Read more**

  1. **Administrative and Legal Reasons**

There are a variety of administrative and legal reasons for which we may share some or all of your information. **Read more**

  1. **Affiliates and Business Transfer**

We may share your information with our Affiliates or in the event of a sale, merger or similar transaction. **Read more**

  1. **Co-Branded Areas**

Co-Branded areas may include information collection by us and third parties. Such Co-Branded Areas will identify the third party and indicate if they have a privacy policy that applies to their collection and use of your information. Such third parties’ privacy policies, not ours, govern their practices. **Read more**

  1. **Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions**

Promotions entrants may be required to consent to certain information sharing. **Read more**

  1. **Your California Privacy Rights**

Users may opt-out of the sharing of certain information with non-Affiliate third parties for direct marketing by letting us know. Often you can exercise such choice at the point of collection, and in all cases by contacting our privacy coordinator. However, we may share your personal information, as defined under California statute, with our Affiliates for their own direct marketing purposes, without checking with you first. California residents may obtain the categories of personal information shared and the names and addresses of all third parties that received such information for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately prior calendar year ( _e.g_., requests made in 2013 will receive information about 2012 sharing activities). **Read more**

**4.What About Information I Disclose Publicly or to Others?**

  1. **User Generated Content and Public Information**

Posting content in public areas makes it available to others. We may share and use your public information for any reason not otherwise prohibited by this Privacy Policy. **Read more**

  1. **Name and Likeness**

You grant us the right to use your name and likeness in connection with your Service-related posting, content and activities. **Read more**

  1. **Profile Settings**

If you decide to become a member of the Service, you may choose to create a Profile associated with your account. We may allow you to populate your Profile with certain content, and we may also associate certain additional content with your Profile based on your interactions with the Service, such as the causes you support and other related activities. From time to time we may offer you Profile settings that allow you to express choices as to how Profile information is made available and to whom, and we will make reasonable, good faith efforts to honor those choices. Any Profile content that we allow you to submit must comply with the restrictions set forth in our **[Terms of Service](http://www.takepart.com/terms-of-use)** at all times. **Read more**

**5.Do Third-Party Content and Links to Third-Party Sites Appear on the Service?**

We may allow you to access third-party content on the Service, or to link to third-party locations from the Service, but we are not responsible for your interaction with third-party content or locations. **Read more**

**6.Ads and Information About You**

We and third parties may send you ads on the Service, including targeted ads based on your location, information and/or behavior. If you object, do not use our Service or exercise choices some third parties may offer. **Read more**

**7.How Do I Change My Information and Communications Preferences?**

You may change certain account information and communications preferences as more fully detailed in this section. **Read more**

**8.What About Transfer of Information to the United States?**

If you are located outside of the United States, you consent to your data being transferred to the United States, which has different data protection laws than other countries. **Read more**

**9.What Should Parents Know About Children?**

We do not intend to collect Personal Information from children under the age of thirteen (13). If you think we have, let us know and we will take corrective action as required by applicable law. **Read more**

**10.What About Security?**

No data security is absolute, but we take reasonable steps to secure data appropriately. **Read more**

**11.What About Changes to the Privacy Policy?**

We may change this Privacy Policy upon posting of a revised Privacy Policy. However, we will continue to treat your Personal Information under the terms of the privacy policy in effect when it was collected unless you otherwise consent. **Read more**

* * *

### **_The Full Detailed Privacy Policy_**

**1\. What Information Does the Service Collect?**

**(a) Information You Provide To Us**

**Personal Information and Demographic Information**. On the Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain categories of information such as: (1) personally identifiable information, which is information that identifies you personally, such as your first and last name and e-mail address (“ **Personal Information** ”); and (2) demographic information, such as information like your zip code, your gender or occupation (“ **Demographic Information** ”). We may collect this information through various forms and in various places on the Service, including newsletter registration forms, through “contact us” forms, or when you otherwise interact with the Service. To the extent we combine Demographic Information with your Personal Information we collect directly from you on the Service ( _e.g._ , petition data may include Personal Information such as name and Demographic Information such as zip code or gender), we will treat the combined data as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.

**(b) Information We Collect and Store as You Access and Use the Service**

In addition to any Personal Information or other information that you choose to submit to us via our Service, we and our third-party service providers may use a variety of technologies that automatically (or passively) store or collect certain information whenever you visit or interact with the Service (“ **Usage Information** ”). This Usage Information may be stored or accessed using a variety of technologies that may be downloaded to your personal computer, browser, laptop, tablet, mobile phone or other device (a “ **Device** ”) whenever you visit or interact with our Service. To the extent we associate Usage Information with your Personal Information we collect directly from you on the Service, we will treat the combined data as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.

This Usage Information may include:

  * your IP address, UDID or other unique identifier (“ **Device Identifier** ”). A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to your Device used to access the Service, and our computers identify your Device by its Device Identifier;
  * your Device functionality (including browser, operating system, hardware, mobile network information);
  * the URL that referred you to our Service;
  * the areas within our Service that you visit and your activities there, including remembering you and your preferences;
  * your Device location;
  * your Device characteristics ( _e.g._ , manufacturer and platform); and
  * certain other Device data, including the time of day of access to ther Service, among other information.

We may use various methods and technologies to store or collect Usage Information (“ **Tracking Technologies** ”). Tracking Technologies may set, change, alter or modify settings or configurations on your Device. A few of the Tracking Technologies include, without limitation, the following (and subsequent technology and methods later developed):

**_Cookies_**. A cookie is a data file placed on a Device when it is used to visit the Service. A Flash cookie (or locally shared object) is a data file placed on a Device via the Adobe Flash plug-in that may be built-in to or downloaded by you to your Device. HTML5 cookies can be programmed through HTML5 local storage. Unlike Flash cookies, HTML5 cookies do not require a plug-in. Regular cookies may generally be disabled or removed by tools that are available as part of most commercial browsers, and in some but not all instances can be blocked in the future by selecting certain settings. Each browser you use will need to be set separately and different browsers offer different functionality and options in this regard. Also, these tools may not be effective with regard to Flash cookies or HTML5 cookies. For information on disabling Flash cookies go to Adobe’s web site at [www.adobe.com](http://www.adobe.com/). Please be aware that if you disable or remove cookies, Flash cookies, or HTML5 cookies on your Device, some parts of our Service may not function properly, and that when you revisit our Service your ability to limit cookies is subject to your browser settings and limitations.

**_Web Beacons_**. Small graphic images or other web programming code called web beacons (also known as “1x1 GIFs” or “clear GIFs”) may be included in our Service's pages and messages. Web beacons may be invisible to you, but any electronic image or other web programming code inserted into a page or e-mail can act as a web beacon. Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count visitors to the Service, to monitor how users navigate the Service, to count how many e-mails that were sent were actually opened or to count how many particular articles or links were actually viewed.

**_Browser Fingerprinting_**. Collection and analysis of information from your Device, such as, without limitation, your operating system, plug-ins, system fonts and other data, for purposes of identification.

**_Embedded Scripts_**. An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with the Service, such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your Device from our web server or a third-party service provider, is active only while you are connected to the Service, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.

**_ETag, or entity tag_**. A feature of the cache in browsers. It is an opaque identifier assigned by a web server to a specific version of a resource found at a URL. If the resource content at that URL ever changes, a new and different ETag is assigned. Used in this manner ETags are a form of Device Identifier. ETag tracking may generate unique tracking values even where the consumer blocks HTTP, Flash and/or HTML5 cookies.

We may use Tracking Technologies for a variety of purposes, including:

**_Strictly Necessary_**. We may use cookies or other Tracking Technologies that we consider are strictly necessary to allow you to use and access our Service, including cookies required to prevent fraudulent activity, improve security or allow you to make use of shopping‑cart functionality.

**_Performance‑Related_**. We may use cookies or other Tracking Technologies that are useful in order to assess the performance of the Service, including as part of our analytic practices or otherwise to improve the content, products or services offered through the Service.

**_Functionality‑Related_**. We may use cookies or other Tracking Technologies that are required to offer you enhanced functionality when accessing the Service, including identifying you when you sign‑in to our Service or keeping track of our specified preferences, including in terms of the presentation of content on our Service.

**_Targeting‑Related_**. We may use Tracking Technologies to deliver content, including ads, relevant to your interests on our Service and third‑party sites based on how you interact with our content. This includes using Tracking Technologies to understand the usefulness to you of the content and advertisements that has been delivered to you. Further information on this, and your opt-out choices, is found in **Section 7.**

There may be other Tracking Technologies now and later devised and used by us in connection with the Service. Further, third parties may use Tracking Technologies in connection with with our Service, which may include the collection of information about your online activities over time and across third-party web sites or online services. We may not control those Tracking Technologies and we are not responsible for them. However, you consent to potentially encountering third-party Tracking Technologies in connection with use of our Service and accept that our statements under this Privacy Policy do not apply to the Tracking Technologies or practices of such third parties. For more information on our vendors, and their Tracking Technologies, Click here. For more information on advertising and advertisers, and related Tracking Technologies, Click here. Also, various third parties are developing or have developed signals or other mechanisms for the expression of consumer choice regarding the collection of information about an individual consumer’s online activities over time and across third-party web sites or online services (e.g., browser do not track signals). Currently, we do not monitor or take any action with respect to these signals or other mechanisms. For more information on third party programs that may permit you to exercise choice regarding targeted advertising based on such information, Click here.

**(c) Information Third Parties Provide About You**

We may receive information about you from your friends and others that use the Service, such as when they submit content to us or post on the Service. Additionally, we may, from time to time, supplement the information we collect directly from you on our Service with outside records from third parties for various purposes, including to enhance our ability to serve you, to tailor our content to you and to offer you opportunities that may be of interest to you. To the extent we combine information we receive from those sources with your Personal Information we collect on the Service, it will be treated as Personal Information and we will apply this Privacy Policy to such combined information, unless we have disclosed otherwise. In no other circumstances do our statements under this Privacy Policy apply to information we receive about you from third parties, even if they have used our technology to collect it and share it with us.

**(d) Interactions with Third-Party Sites**

The Service may include functionality that allows certain kinds of interactions between the Service and your account on a third-party web site or application. The use of this functionality may involve the third-party operator providing certain information, including Personal Information, to us. For example, when you register and create a Profile (defined below) with the Service, you may have an option to register using your Facebook, LinkedIn, Google+ or other account provided by a third-party Service or application, or otherwise link accounts. As part of the process of linking your third-party account to the Service, the third-party service or application may send Personal Information about you to the Service If so, we will then treat it as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy, since we are collecting it as a result of your accessing of and interaction on our Service. In addition, we may provide third-party sites’ interfaces or links on the Service to facilitate your sending a communication from the Service. For example, we may use third parties to facilitate e-mails, tweets or Facebook postings. These third parties may retain any information used or provided in any such communications or other activities and these third parties’ practices are not subject to our Privacy Policy. We may not control or have access to your communications through these third parties. Further, when you use third-party sites or services, you are using their services and not our Service and they, not we, are responsible for their practices. You should review the applicable third-party privacy policies before using such third-party tools on or via our Service.

**(e) Information You Provide About a Third Party**

You may send someone else a communication from the Service, such as sending an invitation to a friend. If so, the information you provide (names, e-mail addresses, mobile number, etc.) is used to facilitate the communication and is not used by us for any other marketing purpose unless we obtain consent from that person or we explicitly say otherwise. Please be aware that when you use any send-to-a-friend functionality on our Service, your e-mail address, mobile number, name or user name and message may be included in the communication sent to your addressee(s).

**2\. How Do We Use the Information Collected?**

We may use your Personal Information, Demographic Information or Usage Information that is subject to this Privacy Policy: (1) to improve the Service or our services, to customize your experience on the Service, or to serve you specific content or advertising that is relevant to you; (2) to enable you to participate in a variety of the Service's features such as online entry sweepstakes, contests or other promotions; (3) to process your registration with the Service, including verifying your information is active and valid; (4) to provide you with information or services or process transactions you have requested or agreed to receive, including to provide you with special offers or promotional materials on behalf of us or third parties; (5) to contact you with regard to your use of the Service and, in our discretion, changes to the Service and/or Service policies; (6) for internal business purposes (such as performance analytics); and (7) for purposes disclosed at the time you provide your information or as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy.

Please note that information submitted to the Service via a “contact us” or other similar function may not receive a response; we will not use that information so provided to contact you for marketing purposes unrelated to your inquiry unless you agree otherwise.

We may share non-Personal Information, such as aggregated user statistics, with third parties. We may also share your Device Identifiers with third parties along with data related to you and your activities. We give you the ability to exercise a choice regarding our sharing of your Personal Information with third parties other than our Affiliates for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes. For example, when we are collecting Personal Information for specific purposes such as where you are taking a social action, we will provide an opt-in or opt-out choice regarding sharing of your Personal Information with specifically designated third parties for them to send you promotional information. We will never just provide your Personal Information from our general database with non-Affiliate third parties for them to send you direct marketing messages without you having first been given the option to opt-in or opt-out of that transfer. However, we may share your Personal Information with our Affiliates such as Participant Media without checking with you first, but California residents may obtain certain information about that as explained in **Section 3(h)** below. Please note that opting in or out for the sharing of Personal Information with third parties for their direct marketing is not an opt-out of social ads or the public nature of User Content (defined below). For more about how to control social ads, see **Section 3(c)**. For more information on User Content, see **Section 4(a)**. In addition, we may share the information we have collected about you (including Personal Information) for other purposes as disclosed at the time you provide your information and as described below or otherwise in this Privacy Policy.

**(a) When You Request Information From or Provide Information to Third Parties**. You may be presented with an option on the Service to receive certain information and/or marketing offers directly from third parties or to have us send certain information to third parties or give them access to it. If you choose to do so, your Personal Information and other information may be disclosed to such third parties and all information you disclose will be subject to the third party privacy policies and practices of such third parties. In addition, third parties may store, collect or otherwise have access to your information when you interact with their Tracking Technologies, content, tools apps or ads on the Service or link to them from our Service. This may include using third-party tools such as Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest or other third-party posting or content sharing tools and by so interacting you consent to such third party practices. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of such third parties and, therefore, you should review such third party privacy policies and practices of such third parties prior to requesting information from or otherwise interacting with them.

**(b) Third Parties Providing Services on Our Behalf**. We may use third-party vendors to perform certain services on behalf of us or the Service, such as hosting the Service, designing and/or operating the Service's features, tracking the Service’s activities and analytics, and enabling us to send you special offers or perform other administrative services. We may provide these vendors with access to user information, including Device Identifiers and Personal Information, to carry out the services they are performing for you or for us. Third party analytics service providers may set and access their own Tracking Technologies on your Device and they may otherwise collect or have access to information about you, separate from our Service, including your Personal Information. We are not responsible for those third-party technologies or activities arising out of them. However, some may offer you certain choices regarding their practices, and information we have been informed of regarding such choices is available here. We are not responsible for the effectiveness of or compliance with any third parties’ opt-out options.

**(c) To Deliver Social Content and Advertising**. We, and others we work with may use your Personal Information, Demographic Information and/or Usage Information we have collected in connection with the Service to target and deliver content, social action opportunities and advertisements to you and other users, on or related to our Service. Further, by using the Service, you consent to the use of your Personal Information and your Service activity information (including regarding your content consumption) in, or in connection with, sponsored content and advertisements shown to your Service connections or other users. For example, by associating your real name, username and/or Profile photo in, or in connection with, sponsored content, social action opportunities and/or advertisements ( _e.g._ , Josh became a fan of Acme, Gabe signed the clean water petition you should too, Gary watched this documentary on dolphin harvesting, etc.). As an example, one of these messages about an action you have taken ( _e.g._ , signing a petition) may be sent to people you have connected with on the Service via the Take Action Platform to prompt a similar action. However, we may, from time to time, offer you options to manage this type of social sharing, and we will, make reasonable good faith efforts to respect settings. However, we do not guarantee that your setting selections will be effective immediately or be error free when delivering social content and advertisements. These settings are the only way to control social ads and messaging; opting out of the sharing of your Personal Information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes is different. You can always avoid social content and ads completely by terminating your account and not using the Service.

**(d) Administrative and Legal Reasons**. To the fullest extent permitted by applicable law, we may access, use, preserve, transfer and disclose your information (including Device Identifiers and Personal Information), including disclosure to third parties: if we believe in good faith that doing so is necessary or appropriate to: (i) protect or defend the rights, safety or property of TakePart or third parties (including through the enforcement of this Privacy Policy, our **Terms of Service** , and other applicable agreements and policies); or (ii) comply with legal and regulatory obligations ( _e.g._ , pursuant to law enforcement inquiries, subpoenas or court orders). To the fullest extent permitted by applicable law, TakePart has complete discretion in electing to make or not make such disclosures, and to contest or not contest requests for such disclosures, all without notice to you.

**(e) Affiliates and Business Transfer**. We may share your information, including your Device Identifiers and Personal Information, Demographic Information and Usage Information with our parent (Participant Media, LLC), and its and our subsidiaries and affiliates (“ **Affiliates** ”). We also reserve the right to disclose and transfer all such information: (i) to a subsequent owner, co-owner or operator of the Service or applicable database; or (ii) in connection with a merger, consolidation, restructuring, the sale of substantially all of our interests and/or assets or other corporate change, including during the course of any due diligence process.

**(f) Co-branded Areas**. Certain areas of the Service may be provided to you in association with third parties (“ **Co-Branded Areas** ”) such as promotional partners and charities, and may require you to disclose Personal Information to them. Such Co-Branded Areas will identify the third party and indicate if they have a privacy policy that applies to their collection and use of you information. If you elect to register for products and/or services, communicate with such third parties or download their content or applications, at Co-Branded Areas, you may be providing your information to both us and the third party. Further, if you sign-in to a Co-Branded Area with a username and password obtained on the Service, your Personal Information may be disclosed to the identified third parties for that Co-Branded Area. We are not responsible for such third party’s data collection or practices and you should look to such third-party privacy policies for more information.

**(g) Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions**. We may offer sweepstakes, contests, and other promotions (any, a “ **Promotion** ”) through the Service that may require registration. By participating in a Promotion, you are agreeing to official rules that govern that Promotion, which may contain specific requirements of you, including, allowing the sponsor of the Promotion to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing associated with the Promotion. If you choose to enter a Promotion, Personal Information may be disclosed to third parties or the public in connection with the administration of such Promotion, including in connection with winner selection, prize fulfillment, and as required by law or permitted by the Promotion’s official rules, such as on a winners list.

**(h) Your California Privacy Rights**. California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents who have supplied personal information, as defined in the statute, to us to, under certain circumstances, request and obtain certain information regarding our disclosure, if any, of such information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. We provide the option to all of our users to exercise choice regarding this type of data transfer to non-Affiliate third parties, as more fully described above in the first paragraph of this Section 3. Please note that this direct marketing transfer choice is different from the choices you may have regarding social ads and content, which are explained in **Section 3(c)** , or your User Content, which is explained in **Section 4(a)**. With respect to the sharing of your personal information, as defined in the statute, with our Affiliates for their own direct marketing purposes, however, we may share such information with our Affiliates such as Participant Media without checking with you first. California residents may obtain the categories of personal information shared and the names and addresses of all third parties that received such information for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately prior calendar year ( _e.g_., requests made in 2013 will receive information about 2012 sharing activities). To make such a request, please provide sufficient information for us to determine if this applies to you, attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for our response. You may make this request by writing to us at: Postal Mail: TakePart, LLC, 331 Foothill Road, 3rd Floor, Beverly Hills, CA 90210 (Attn: Privacy Coordinator); E-mail: [privacy@takepart.com](mailto:privacy@takepart.com).

**4\. What About Information I Disclose Publicly or to Others?**

**(a) User Generated Content and Public Information**. The Service may permit you to submit ideas, photographs, Profiles, writings, video, audio recordings, computer graphics, pictures, data, questions, comments, suggestions or other content, including Personal Information (collectively, “ **User Content** ”), such as on your Profile, petitions you sign and group boards. We or others may store, display, reproduce, publish, distribute or otherwise use User Content online or offline in any media or format (currently existing or hereafter developed) and may or may not attribute it to you. Others may have access to this User Content and may have the ability to share it with third parties. Please think carefully before deciding what information you share, including Personal Information, in connection with your User Content. Please note that we do not control who will have access to the information that you choose to make public, and cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy or keep it secure. We are not responsible for the privacy or security of any information that you make publicly available on the Service or for what others do with the information you share with them. We are not responsible for the accuracy, use or misuse of any User Content that you disclose or receive from third parties through the Service.

**(b) Name and Likeness**. We may also publish your name, voice, likeness and other Personal Information that is part of your User Content, and we may use the content, or any portion of the content, for advertising, marketing, publicity and promotional activities. This includes use in connection with social content and ads as more fully explained in **Section 3(c)**. For full terms and conditions regarding User Content you submit to the Service, please review our **[Terms of Service](http://www.takepart.com/terms-of-use)**.

**(c) Profile Settings**. A user’s profile (“ **Profile** ”) page may be, by default, set up to display information such as the user’s display name, Profile photo, images, location (city/state), groups that the user has joined and optional information added by the user including, for example, the user’s tagline, photographs, social initiatives, and previous actions taken and causes supported, etc. If you register using Facebook Connect or another third party service, your Profile will be by that action populated based on what information you elect to let that service share with us. If your register directly on our Service, or supplement your Profile via the Service, you will directly enter what information your Profile will include. Profile information is used by us primarily to be presented back to you when you access the Service and to be presented to others permitted to view that information on or in connection with the Service. In some cases ( _e.g._ , posting to your page), other users of the Service may be able to supplement your Profile. We may offer users the ability to manage their Profile and use Profile preference settings, the functionality and features of which are subject to change from time-to-time so visit the settings available frequently to confirm the settings reflect your then current preferences and we recommend that you do not post information or content as part of your Profile that you are not prepared to make completely public. Changing setting options may not result in immediate changes to the settings, which are subject to our operations and maintenance schedules. Changing information or preferences using third party applications like Facebook Connect, is dependent upon the performance of such third parties for which we are not responsible. Users should carefully consider the use of preference settings to improve information display options and should regularly ensure the settings are properly set and functioning in the manner desired. Notwithstanding the availability of Profile preference settings, you should be aware that these settings are for convenience only, do not employ complex data security protection and may not be error free. Further, other users that have access may repost or otherwise make public your information or content. Accordingly, discretion and good judgment should be exercised when posting information or content as part of your Profile.

**5\. Do Third-Party Content and Links To Third-Party Sites Appear on the Service?**

The Service may contain content that is supplied by a third party, and those third parties may collect Usage Information and your Device Identifier when pages from the Service are served to you. In addition, when you are on the Service you may be directed to other services such as applications that are operated and controlled by third parties that we do not control. We are not responsible for the data collection and privacy practices employed by any of these third parties or their services and they may be tracking you across multiple sites and may be sharing the results of that tracking with us and/or others. For example, if you “click” on a link, the “click” may take you off the Service onto a different service. These other sites may have their own terms of service, privacy policies or other policies and ask you to agree to the same as well as associate their Tracking Technologies with you, independently collect data about you, including Personal Information, and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. We encourage you to note when you leave our Service and to review the third-party privacy policies of all third-party locations and exercise caution in connection with them.

**6\. Ads and Information About You**

The Service may use third parties such as network advertisers and ad exchanges to serve advertisements on and off of the Service and may use third-party analytics and other service providers to evaluate and provide us and/or third parties with information about the use of the Service and viewing of ads and of our content. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits and activities across the Internet and mobile media (“ **Behavioral Ads** ”). In addition, we may serve ads on our Service based on your Usage Information from your activities on our Service (“ **Contextual Ads** ”). Behavioral Ads and Contextual Ads enable us to target advertisements to you for products and services in which you might be interested. If you object to Contextual Ads, do not use our Service. If you object to Behavioral Ads from us on third-party sites, you can learn more about your ability to limit Behavioral Ads below.

Our third-party ad network and exchange providers, the advertisers, the sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own cookies (including Flash cookies), web beacons and other Tracking Technologies on your Device and track certain behavioral Usage Information regarding users of your Device via a Device Identifier. These third-party Tracking Technologies may be set to, among other things: (a) help deliver advertisements to you that you might be interested in; (b) prevent you from seeing the same advertisements too many times; and (c) understand the usefulness to you of the advertisements that have been delivered to you. You acknowledge and agree that associated technology may access and use your Device and may set or change settings on your Device in connection with the associated operations. Note that any images (or any other parts of content) served by third parties in association with third-party ads or other content may serve as web beacons, which enable third parties to carry out the previously described activities.

Third-party Tracking Technologies are not controlled by us, even if they are used to serve our ads or interact with our Service. Statements regarding our practices do not apply to the methods for collecting information used by these third parties or the use of the information that such third parties collect. We do however work with third parties to make efforts to have you provided with information on their practices and any available opportunity to exercise choice. The relevant third party’s terms of service, privacy policy, permissions, notices and choices should be reviewed regarding their collection, storage and sharing practices. We make no representations regarding the policies or practices of third-party advertisers or advertising networks or exchanges or related third parties.

However, some third parties we work with may offer you certain choices regarding their practices, and information we have been informed of regarding such choices is available information we have been informed of regarding such choices is available **here**. Further, while we and third-party sites that display our ads may use a variety of companies to serve advertisements, you may wish to visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>, which provides information regarding this practice by Network Advertising Initiative (“ **NAI** ”) members, and your choices regarding having this information used by these companies, including the “opt-out” procedures of NAI members. Opting out of one or more NAI members only means that those NAI members no longer will be allowed under their own rules to deliver Behavioral Ads to you, which will affect this and other sites, but does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content and/or ads. Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you visit this opt-out page, or you subsequently erase your cookies, use a different Device or change web browsers, your NAI opt-out may not, or may no longer, be effective. Therefore, if you use multiple Devices or multiple browsers on a single Device, you need to opt-out by clicking the orange opt-out icon for each browser that you use on your Device. Additionally, if you delete your cookies, change browsers, or use a different Device, you will need to opt-out again. Additional information is available on the NAI’s web site accessible by the above link. Where we serve third-party Behavioral Ads on the [Service](http://www.takepart.com/terms-of-use) we participate in the notice and opt-out program run by the Digital Advertising Alliance (“ **DAA** ”), and you can learn more about it and the opt-out choices it offers at <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/#completed>. Where we serve our own Behavioral Ads on third-party sites, we request that they comply with the DAA program so that you have the same notice and opt-out choice. Please note that similar limitations as described regarding NAI opt-out may apply to the DAA opt-out. In the event that we allow third parties to display advertisements that are directly targeted at users in the EU, please visit [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/) to learn more about your options. Similar limitations may apply to these opt-out methods. Although we take commercial reasonable efforts to comply with the DAA Behavioral Ad Principles, we are not responsible for effectiveness of, or compliance with, any third-parties’ opt-out options or programs.

**7\. How Do I Change My Information and Communications Preferences?**

You are responsible for maintaining the accuracy of the information we receive about you, such as your contact information provided as part of registration and Profile creation. When you use Facebook Connect, or another third party service, to sign in or sign up changes you make to that third party account that information you have elected to have that third party share with us when you activated that service on our Services should automatically update your account, however, since we do not control Facebook or other third party services, we cannot be responsible for this occurring promptly or accurately. If you terminate your Facebook account, your ability to access your account on our Service via Facebook Connect will no longer be available, and the same applies with respect to other third party services. To the extent we allow account registrations directly on our Service (i.e., other than by means of Facebook Connect or other third party services), the Service will also include functionality to allow you to review, correct or update your registration and Profile. If you utilize this functionality, we will make good faith efforts to make requested changes in our then active databases as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note that it is not always possible to completely remove or delete all of your information from our databases and that residual data may remain on backup media or for other reasons. Also, if you have made any public postings on the Service such as User Content in forums or blogs, these communications cannot generally be removed. When you edit your Personal Information or change your preferences on the Service, information that you remove may persist internally for our administrative purposes. You may cancel or modify our e-mail marketing communications you receive from us by following the instructions contained within our promotional e-mails or in some cases by logging into your Service Account and changing your communication preferences. This will not affect subsequent subscriptions and if your opt-out is limited to certain types of e-mails the opt-out will be so limited. If you subscribe to text messages from us, you can terminate a particular text message subscription by reply texting “STOP.” Subsequent or different subscriptions will be unaffected. Please note that we reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to your account or use of our Service, such as administrative and service announcements and these transactional account messages may be unaffected if you choose to opt-out from receiving our marketing communications. If you have any questions about the Privacy Policy or practices described in it, you should contact us in the following ways: Postal Mail: TakePart, LLC, 331 Foothill Road, 3rd Floor, Beverly Hills, California 90210 (Attn: Privacy Coordinator); By e-mail: [privacy@takepart.com](mailto:privacy@takepart.com).

**8\. What About Transfer of Information to the United States?**

Our Service is operated in the United States and intended for users located in the United States. If you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that information we collect, including Personal Information, will be transferred to, and processed, stored and used in the United States. The data protection laws in the United States may differ from those of the country in which you are located, and your Personal Information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in the United States according to laws of the United States. By using the Service or providing us with any information, you consent to the transfer to, and processing, usage, sharing and storage of your information, including Personal Information, in the United States as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**9\. What Should Parents Know About Children?**

The Service is intended for general audiences and we do not knowingly collect any Personal Information from children younger than the age of thirteen (13) as required by U.S. law. We will delete any Personal Information collected that we later determine to be from a user younger than the age of thirteen (13). If you are a parent or guardian of a child under the age of thirteen (13) and believe he or she has disclosed Personal Information to us, please contact us at [privacy@takepart.com](mailto:privacy@takepart.com).

**10\. What About Security?**

We incorporate commercially reasonable safeguards to help protect and secure your Personal Information. However, no data transmission over the Internet, mobile networks, wireless transmission or electronic storage of information can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Please note that we cannot ensure the security of any information you transmit to us, and you use our Service and provide us with your information at your own risk.

**11\. What About Changes to the Privacy Policy?**

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time without notice to you. Any changes will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Privacy Policy. However, we will not use your previously collected Personal Information in a manner materially different than represented at the time it was collected without your consent. To the extent any provision of this Privacy Policy is found by a competent tribunal to be invalid or unenforceable, such provision shall be severed to the extent necessary for the remainder to be valid and enforceable.

© 2008-2014 TakePart, LLC.

* * *

The following third parties that collect information from you on or in connection with our Service(s) have given us notice that you may obtain information on their policies and practices, and in some instances opt-out of certain of their activities, as follows:

**Party**

| 

**Service**

| 

**For More Information**

| 

**Use of Tracking Technologies**

| 

**Privacy Choices or Information**  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
  
AddThis

| 

Widget

| 

<http://www.addthis.com/about>

| 

Yes

| 

<http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out>  
  
Adobe SiteCatalyst

| 

Analytics

| 

<http://www.adobe.com/solutions/digital-analytics/marketing-reports-analytics.html>

| 

Yes

| 

Adobe Site Catalyst data is used for internal purposes only and not shared with any third-party.  
  
AdoTube

| 

Audience Discovery

| 

<http://exponential.com/our-company/privacy/>

| 

Yes

| 

<http://exponential.com/success/>  
  
AdRoll

| 

Ad Serving

| 

<http://www.adroll.com/about/privacy>

| 

Yes

| 

<http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>  
  
AdXpose

| 

Analytics

| 

<http://www.adxpose.com/about/about.page>

| 

Yes

| 

<http://www.adxpose.com/privacyPolicy.page>  
  
Aggregate Knowledge

| 

Analytics

| 

<http://www.aggregateknowledge.com/company/about-us/>

| 

Yes

| 

<http://www.aggregateknowledge.com/privacy/ak-optout/>  
  
Casale Media

| 

Ad Serving

| 

<http://casalemedia.com/privacy/>

| 

Yes

| 

<http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>  
  
DoubleClick for Small Business

| 

Ad Serving Software

| 

<http://www.google.com/doubleclick/publishers/small-business/>

| 

Yes

| 

DoubleClick for Small Business data is used for internal purposes only and not shared with any third-party.  
  
Facebook

| 

User Authentication & Commenting

| 

<https://www.facebook.com/help/privacy>

| 

Yes

| 

Registering for a TakePart account as a user and commenting on TakePart content are optional features that a user may use or refrain from using in its sole discretion.   
  
Federated Media

| 

Ad Serving

| 

<http://www.federatedmedia.net/privacy-policy/>

| 

Yes

| 

<http://www.federatedmedia.net/privacy-policy/#opt-out>  
  
Google AdSense

| 

Ad Serving

| 

<http://www.google.com/ads/displaynetwork/>

| 

Yes

| 

<http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/html/opt-out.html>  
  
Google Analytics

| 

Analytics

| 

<http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>

| 

Yes

| 

<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>  
  
Google+

| 

User Authentication

| 

<https://plus.google.com/settings>

| 

Yes

| 

Registering for a TakePart account as a user is an optional feature that a user may use or refrain from using in its sole discretion.   
  
Insight Express

| 

Ad Measurement

| 

<http://www.insightexpress.com/company>

| 

Yes

| 

<http://www.insightexpress.com/privacy-policy>  
  
MaxMind

| 

Geographic Location (country level)

| 

<https://twitter.com/privacy>

| 

No

| 

Some TakePart content is restricted based on the country from which the user is accessing it.  
  
Optimizely

| 

A/B Testing

| 

<https://www.optimizely.com/about>

| 

Yes

| 

<https://www.optimizely.com/opt_out>  
  
Omniture

| 

Analytics

| 

<http://www.adobe.com/privacy/analytics.html>

| 

Yes

| 

<http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html#4>  
  
PubMatic

| 

Ad Management

| 

<http://www.pubmatic.com/about-us.php>

| 

Yes

| 

<http://www.pubmatic.com/opt-out.php>  
  
ScoreCard Research

| 

Ad Research

| 

<http://www.fullcirclestudies.com/about.aspx>

| 

Yes

| 

<http://www.fullcirclestudies.com/privacy.aspx>  
  
Quantcast

| 

Audience Measurement

| 

<https://www.quantcast.com/how-we-do-it/consumer-choice/privacy-policy/>

| 

Yes

| 

<https://www.quantcast.com/opt-out>  
  
Tribal Fusion

| 

Audience Discovery

| 

<http://exponential.com/our-company/privacy/>

| 

Yes

| 

<http://exponential.com/success/>  
  
Twitter

| 

User Authentication

| 

<https://twitter.com/privacy>

| 

Yes

| 

Registering for a TakePart account as a user is an optional feature that a user may use or refrain from using in its sole discretion.   
  
Waterfall Mobile

| 

SMS Marketing

| 

<http://www.waterfallmobile.com/>

| 

No

| 

Waterfall Mobile data is used for internal purposes only and not shared with any third-party.  
  
NOTE: We are not responsible for third-party policies or practices. We try to keep this information current, but it is provided as a courtesy and may not be current or accurate. Please contact the applicable third parties regarding their privacy and data security policies and practices.
